<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gear | Jack Baty - the archives]]></title>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/blog/categories/gear/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T23:15:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack Baty]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jack@jackbaty.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[patrickrhone - My Daily Pens]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/patrickrhone-my-daily-pens/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-12T17:33:02-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/patrickrhone-my-daily-pens</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://patrickrhone.com/2012/01/12/mydailypens/">My Daily Pens</a></p>

<blockquote><p>These are the pens I carry on me daily</p></blockquote>

<p>I started to watch this with fascination, until I realized it was a video about what pens he carries. PENS! And I was <em>riveted</em> there for a minute.</p>

<p>Just shoot me.</p>

<p>(I'm not picking on Patrick specifically. I enjoy his site, but sometimes I need to find something else to do)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bag Problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/12/bag-problem/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-17T14:20:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/12/bag-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2011/12/20111217_PC171948-processed.jpg" alt="Some of the many bags I've accidentally purchased" /></p>

<p>I wouldn't call it a "problem," exactly. "Condition" might be a better word for my interest in bags. It's not that I love bags so much as I love trying to find one that's perfect. Of course there is no such thing, which is why I've ended up with so many. The photo above shows a few of them that happened to end up in my kitchen.</p>

<p>Clockwise from left:</p>

<ul>
<li>Some generic Lowepro camera backpack. Good for hiking, which I never do.</li>
<li>Jack Spade tote. Nice, general carry-all.</li>
<li>Domke camera bag. I forget the model. Never grew to like this one. Odd size and shape never really fit with me.</li>
<li>Pelican hard case. It's ancient and still tough as nails. My Hasselblad kit lives in here - safely.</li>
<li>Ari Marcopoulos Camera Bag. This is a newcomer and it's very promising. I'll post something later about it, maybe.</li>
<li>Maxwell Scott briefcase. This is what I bring to the office every day. Fits the Macbook Air and iPad, a notebook with a few pens and such. Very high quality leather and construction costs more, but the fit, finish, and feel of this bag is fantastic. It even smells great.</li>
<li>Domke F-803 Satchel. Really great bag. Nearly perfect. This has been my most-carried camera bag for years. A couple of rangefinders and some film fit perfectly. It's small, well-made bag, and works great for walking about with a small kit. Only thing I'd change is that it uses velcro pocket closures. Noisy and blech.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reconfiguring my Cameras]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/06/reconfiguring-my-cameras/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-05T18:38:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/06/reconfiguring-my-cameras</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shooting film is something that I've been doing for quite a while now. I own a half-dozen or more wonderful film cameras. I have scanners for digital display and a darkroom for making prints. It's all very cool and interesting. There is something about shooting film that is magical and cannot be replaced by digital means. It's also a pain in the ass and I'm running out of patience. Scanning 36 exposures of 35mm film is a horrible process that eats up an hour or two every time. That would be ok if the results I was getting were worth it. They're not. On the other hand, I love the results I get from the medium format cameras. So let's just say 35mm film is out, but 6x6 is in.</p>

<p>Now what? The answer, I'm almost ashamed to say, should maybe be digital. I've been thinking about what's next for weeks. My first reflex told me that I wanted to replace my Leica M cameras with an M9. I owned the earlier M8 briefly but didn't like the compromises it required (cropped sensor and IR issues.) The M9 is much more attractive, but at $7000 it would be a life-changing investment for me. Leica rangefinders have a fairly limited range, photographically speaking, and spending that kind of money on an M9 would mean I'd need to be limited by that range as well.</p>

<p>The question to ask is what kind of shooting do I do? Truth is, not much. That realization hurts a little, but there it is. I tinker, mostly. To a normal person, that would mean that any little point and shoot would be enough, but I'm not normal. What I want to shoot are portraits, some "street" and possibly some fine art things I haven't even thought of yet. I also don't want to give up medium format film - it's just too great. And I don't want to always wish I'd gotten a better camera.</p>

<p>I'm now thinking I'll own 3 cameras.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2011/06/Hasselblad-500-Classic-1990-1992.jpg" alt="Hasselblad 500 Classic 1990 1992" /></p>

<p><strong>Hasselblad 500C/M</strong>. I already own this camera, and a couple of terrific Zeiss lenses, film backs, prisms, and cases to go with it. The Hasselblad is a very frustrating camera to use at times, but I just love the results. Besides, it's like a work of art and an engineering miracle all rolled into one even when it's sitting on a shelf. I'm keeping it.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2011/06/nikond700.jpg" alt="Nikond700" /></p>

<p><strong>Nikon D700</strong> There's a reason everyone walks around with a big-ass DSLR all the time. They're versatile, fast, and they do a great job. I keep selling my DSLRs because they're uninteresting and I hate walking around looking like every other schmuck. But, the D700 is a terrific camera. I've owned the D300 and loved the autofocus and flash system. The D700 is full-frame, built very well, and does wonders in low light. It's an obvious choice for just about any type of photography, and I should have one.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2011/06/fuji-x100-04.jpg" alt="Fuji x100 04" /></p>

<p><strong>Fuji X100</strong> For everything else, for just walking around, and for the serious cool of it, I want the X100. An APS-C sensor and a real optical viewfinder. Plus a retro cool look and feel that fits my tastes exactly. This will be the camera I carry with me everywhere, replacing the M4 I use now. Not the same, but not so different either.</p>

<p>So I'm covered. Medium format film, do-everything DSLR, and compact cameras. Sounds good to me.</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE - November 24, 2011</strong></p>

<p>I was close. The D700 is indeed an awesome camera. Auto ISO up to 3200 results in the cleanest available light photos I've ever seen. Really terrific.</p>

<p>The X100 never really captured me enough to try. Fixed lens point-and-shoot cameras make sense, but something with the image quality of the X100 begs for interchangeable lenses, so I purchased an Olympus E-P3 with viewfinder instead. Nice camera, and I can put all sorts of interesting lenses on it.</p>

<p>What I didn't expect back in June was that I would enjoy the D700 but wish it took film. As much as I find film to be a pain in the ass, I still prefer it. So I went all out and <a href="http://jackbaty.com/2011/11/nikon-f6/">bought an F6</a>. It's everything everyone said it would be. I love it.</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE - December 24, 2011</strong></p>

<p>Ok, I did end up <a href="http://jackbaty.com/2011/12/fuji-x100/">buying an X100</a> and so far I'm glad I did. Now I need to decide whether or not to sell the E-P3. And so it goes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I install on a new computer - revisited Fall 2009]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/11/things-i-install-on-a-new-computer-revisited-fall-2009/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-28T10:44:58-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/11/things-i-install-on-a-new-computer-revisited-fall-2009</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/macbookpro-unibody.png" alt="macbookpro-unibody.png" /></p>

<p>My new MacBook Pro arrived yesterday. This will replace my aging, 2-year old version. It's a thing of beauty. Whenever I get a new machine, I'm tempted to just run the simple data migration to move everything over, but never do. Instead, I start from scratch. This is a complete pain in the ass, but very much worth the trouble. It just feels so good!</p>

<p>Below is a list of things I installed this time. I'm listing only software, not the geeky bits like Ruby On Rails, MacPorts etc. It took me most of the day yesterday, but I think I've got things pretty much how I like them.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.obdev.at/launchbar">Launchbar</a> - Without a good launcher, using a Mac feels like working
with one hand behind my back.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/">Dropbox</a> - Sync made so easy it's ridiculous.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.eastgate.com/Tinderbox/">Tinderbox</a> - "The tool for notes" (and nearly everything else.) This is where I live.</li>
<li><a href="http://agilewebsolutions.com/products/1Password">1Password</a> - Passwords, forms, card numbers, etc. Beautifully done.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.barebones.com/products/Yojimbo/">Yojimbo</a> - An anything bucket. Simple enough that it actually gets used.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.barebones.com/products/bbedit/">BBEdit</a> - Text editing done very well. Yes, better than TextMate.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.omnigroup.com/applications/omnifocus/">OmniFocus</a> - Task management with enough oomph.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.appzapper.com/">AppZapper</a> - I change my mind a lot.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.backblaze.com/">Backblaze</a> - Online backup without thinking. Just in case.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.busymac.com/">BusyCal</a> - Because iCal isn't good enough, and I don't like web based calendars.</li>
<li><a href="http://marketcircle.com/">Daylite</a> - Gotta put all those contacts and opportunities somewhere.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.devon-technologies.com/products/devonthink/">DEVONthink Pro</a> - Anything project related goes here, and I'm guaranteed to find it.</li>
<li><a href="http://fluidapp.com/">Fluid</a> - For running web stuff as their own "apps".</li>
<li><a href="http://www.interarchy.com/">Interarchy</a> - SFTP client. I've been using this for years. No reason to change.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.red-sweater.com/marsedit/">MarsEdit</a> - Still the best way to consistently post to a number of sites.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mindjet.com/">MindManager</a> - Mindmapping. Expensive, but still the best there is.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newsgator.com/INDIVIDUALS/NETNEWSWIRE/">NetNewsWire</a> - Because even the good web-based readers suck.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.ommwriter.com/">OmmWriter</a>- Weird, new-agey writing app for distraction-free writing. Surprised by how much I like it.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.camerabits.com/">Photo Mechanic</a> - Not used as much now that I don't shoot digital, but it's great for pulling photos of cards when I do.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.hogbaysoftware.com/products/quickcursor/">QuickCursor</a> - Like the "Edit In..." plugins, without the hacks.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sequelpro.com/">Sequel Pro</a> - Best MySQL management GUI available.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.irradiatedsoftware.com/sizeup/">SizeUp</a> - Move and size windows with the keyboard.</li>
<li><a href="http://skitch.com/">Skitch</a> - Almost perfect screen capture.</li>
<li><a href="http://drikin.com/spiritedaway/">Spirited Away</a> - Automatically hides inactive apps. Fits my minimalist tendencies nicely.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.shirt-pocket.com/SuperDuper/SuperDuperDescription.html">SuperDuper</a> - Simple, bootable backups. Saved my ass a number of times.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.the-soulmen.com/ulysses/">Ulysses</a> - Complete semantic writing environment.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.hogbaysoftware.com/products/writeroom">WriteRoom</a> - Distraction free writing.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/photoshoplightroom/">Lightroom</a> - Image management and editing. Does everything.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.niksoftware.com/completecollection/es/entry.php?">Nik Plugins for Lightroom</a> - The Complete Collection. Awesome set of tools for Lightroom.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.silverfast.com/">SilverFast Ai Studio</a> - The best scanning results, with the worst UI of any software, anywhere.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.smileonmymac.com/TextExpander/">TextExpander</a> - Wonderful typing utility/accelerator. I'm lost without this.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.islayer.com/apps/istatmenus/">iStat Menus</a> - Very nice system monitors. I use the menu bar calendar instead of the built in version.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.indev.ca/MailActOn.html">Mail Act-On</a> - Keyboard email management for Mail.app.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.econtechnologies.com/pages/cs/chrono_overview.html">Chronosync</a> - Synchronizes all my external drives nicely, automatically, on a schedule.</li>
<li><a href="http://flyingmeat.com/acorn/">Acorn</a> - It really is "The image editor for humans." I despise Photoshop, and now I don't need it.</li>
<li><a href="http://rentzsch.github.com/clicktoflash/">ClickToFlash</a> - Great Safari plug-in which gets Flash under control.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Marco Arment on his new Magic Mouse]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/11/marco-arment-on-his-new-magic-mouse/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-13T14:47:17-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/11/marco-arment-on-his-new-magic-mouse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Marco Arment on Apple's Magic Mouse:</p>

<blockquote><p>"But it comes with a cost. Setting the auto-unlock wheel mode requires the Logitech software, which screws with the standard OS X pointer sensitivity and scrolling acceleration. To get mine to work the way it should, I had to install Logitech's software to enable the auto-unlock wheel, uninstall it, and install SteerMouse instead to enable most other functionality."</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.marco.org/242751156">Marco.org</a></p>

<p>He describes my experience <em>exactly</em>. I love the MX. Best mouse I'd ever used, but the new Magic Mouse is better. Smaller, simpler, works. Buying a second one for the house this weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
