<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Jack Baty - the archives]]></title>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T23:05:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack Baty]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jack@jackbaty.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the Archives of jackbaty.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/05/welcome-to-the-archives-of-jackbaty-dot-com/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T23:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/05/welcome-to-the-archives-of-jackbaty-dot-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at archives.jackbaty.com you&#8217;ll find over 1600 posts I&#8217;ve written over the
past 10 years. Sometimes it&#8217;s good to start fresh, which I&#8217;ve done. All the new
stuff will be available at http://www.jackbaty.com/</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deciding between the old and the new]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/04/deciding-between-the-old-and-the-new/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T15:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/04/deciding-between-the-old-and-the-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://archives.jackbaty.com/images/2012/fuji-and-m4.jpg" alt="Fuji X-Pro1 and Leica M4" /></p>

<p>I&#8217;m never going to &#8220;go completely digital&#8221; or &#8220;use only film&#8221; since I cannot completely give up either. Not that I haven&#8217;t tried. One day I convince myself the only thing that matters is film, and I buy the greatest film camera I can think of because that&#8217;s all I&#8217;ll ever need or use ever ever again. A week (or month) goes by and I decide I&#8217;m frustrated with scanning or whatever and I think I&#8217;d prefer something quick and easy, so I find some new hot digital camera that will solve all my problems.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s never going to end, I know that. But knowing doesn&#8217;t help.</p>

<p>For example, I recently had a disappointing week shooting film in low light. Tri-X shot at 1250 ISO and processed in Diafine does pretty well, but even that pushes shutter speeds down to 1/30th or so and inevitably motion blur ruins everything. Tired of fighting it, I looked to digital.</p>

<p>I &#8220;solved&#8221; the problem by buying a Fuji X-Pro1 and a couple of lenses. How does that solve the problem? Well, I love the hybrid viewfinder, analog controls, and of course the excellent high ISO performance. ISO 6400 is usable, and The Fujinon 35mm 1.4 is plenty fast. Boom! It&#8217;s like best of both worlds.</p>

<p>Except then I picked up my trusty Leica M4. There&#8217;s nothing like the feel of that camera. It&#8217;s visceral. Besides, what else does one need? No batteries or whizbang features to get in the way. Pure photography! And I have an awesome and under-utilized wet darkroom just begging for more film, so I start shopping again.</p>

<p>You see how it is? It&#8217;s a grand form of rationalization. Eventually, I&#8217;ll need to accept the fact that I really love the very old film process as well as and the very newest digital wizardry. It&#8217;ll have to be both. There, that&#8217;s settled. Right?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calepin is closing]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/04/calepin-is-closing/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-21T09:22:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/04/calepin-is-closing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>And of course as soon as I find something I really like, it closes.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>Announcement: Calepin is closing in 90 days. Consider moving to @<a href="https://twitter.com/scriptogram">scriptogram</a> Thanks for the ride. Sorry I couldn&#8217;t maintain it.</p>&mdash; Calepin (@calepinapp) <a href="https://twitter.com/calepinapp/status/192335906479415296" data-datetime="2012-04-17T19:37:08+00:00">April 17, 2012</a></blockquote>


<script src="http://archives.jackbaty.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>That&#8217;s unfortunate, because Calepin really is (was) a nice, easy, Markdown
and Dropbox based blogging service. Guess I&#8217;ll be investigating <a href="http://scriptogr.am/">Scriptogr.am</a> as a replacement.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Calepin is Calling]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/calepin-is-calling/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-24T15:03:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/calepin-is-calling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As much as I like the end result of this blog using Octopress, getting there
isn&#8217;t as easy as I&#8217;d like.</p>

<p><a href="http://calepin.co">Calepin</a> on the other hand, lacks almost every feature of
modern blogging platforms. This is not a bad thing. Also, Calepin fits how I
think, and makes publishing so easy it&#8217;s silly.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve had a Calepin blog, <a href="http://copingmechanism.com/">CopingMechanism.com</a> for
a few months now and really like it. The latest post goes into a bit more
detail into my <a href="http://copingmechanism.com/octopress-or-calepin.html">Octopress vs. Calepin dilemma</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Hosed the RSS Feed Again]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/i-hosed-the-rss-feed-again/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-24T07:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/i-hosed-the-rss-feed-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To the handful of you subscribed to the RSS feed here, I apologize for messing things up again. First, I changed blogging platforms, which modified some of the post titles. Then a couple of days ago, I thought I&#8217;d try running the entire blog out of an Amazon S3 bucket. This worked great, but required that I use a subdomain rather than the apex. The feed was pointing at jackbaty.com,  which is now redirected to www.jackbaty.com, causing duplicate entries.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll try not to do that again, but as soon as a static blogging platform comes along that works as well as Octopress, but with fewer dependencies, I will probably want to try it, so no promises.</p>

<p>Otherwise, using an S3 bucket for hosting a static site is pretty slick. No need to run or share a server, no Apache config, etc. Since I use <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> everything is generated locally, so to &#8220;publish&#8221; changes I use <a href="http://s3tools.org/s3cmd">s3cmd</a> to sync things. There are a couple of pull requests waiting to be pulled into Octopress which will take care of that for me with the built-in &#8220;rake deploy&#8221; task, but for now I do it manually.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Road Rage]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/road-rage/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-22T17:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/road-rage</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I become angry while driving. Not mildly annoyed, but full-on vein-popping, teeth-grittingly furious. This isn&#8217;t the exception either. It happens nearly every time I get behind the wheel.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not normally aggressive or prone to violence. In fact, I&#8217;d consider myself a pretty mild-mannered fella. Very roll-with-the-punches, I&#8217;d say. And yet, I am consumed with road rage during even the most basic commute. It&#8217;s not healthy.</p>

<p>I could relax while driving if people would simply remember a few of the rules we all learned in kindergarten.</p>

<ol>
<li>No cutting in line for any reason</li>
<li>You are not the only person who matters</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t be such a DICK!</li>
</ol>


<p>That&#8217;s it. Follow those rules and I&#8217;m Mr. Happy. Ignore them and I go all self-appointed-vigilante, tensing up and spewing obscenities. I&#8217;m not looking for a fight. Honest. I simply feel the need to let folks know in no uncertain terms that they&#8217;ve just made a dick move and should stop doing that. Yelling and getting angry doesn&#8217;t help, which is something <em>I</em> should have learned in kindergarten. Despite my efforts, people still drive like assholes. The only likely outcome is that I&#8217;m going to die of a heart attack or gunshot wound.</p>

<p>If I can&#8217;t fix anyone else, I suppose I&#8217;m going to have to fix myself.</p>

<p>For the past week I&#8217;ve been practicing. I smile kindly at the guy sneaking out-of-turn through the 4-way stop. I just quietly shake my head when someone decides that turn signals are too much hassle to bother with. Deep Breaths help.</p>

<p>So far it&#8217;s only been mildly successful, and I&#8217;m looking forward to the day when I arrive at my destination with unclenched teeth.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 Photo Album]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/2012-photo-album/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T18:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/2012-photo-album</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://archives.jackbaty.com/images/20120319__DSC5849-processed.jpg"></p>

<p>I&#8217;m building an honest-to-goodness photo album this year. Each print is made in
the darkroom and each caption is hand-written. Not a pixel in sight.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a hand-made family heirloom, that&#8217;s what it is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Process is not the Point]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/the-process-is-not-the-point/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-18T17:17:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/the-process-is-not-the-point</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Joshua Porter:</p>

<blockquote><p>And then there is the Point. The problem you’re trying to solve. The thing that isn’t part of a process but is the most important thing you need to focus on as a designer. The thing that, if you happen to solve it, makes the process almost irrelevant. Solve the problem and you’re successful no matter what process you’ve been using.</p></blockquote>

<p>I have the most fun screwing around with the Process. Most of us do, but
none of it matters if we miss the Point.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Floundering]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/why-i-didnt-go-to-sxsw-jay-parkinson/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-14T18:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/why-i-didnt-go-to-sxsw-jay-parkinson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jay Parkinson:</p>

<blockquote><p>SXSW was important back in the day when real problems were still being solved by the internet. Now that the internet has solved the vast majority of real honest to god problems we humans have, it’s floundering. And I just don’t have the time nor the interest.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Operation Everything Goes Into Evernote]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/operation-everthing-goes-into-evernote/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T19:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/operation-everthing-goes-into-evernote</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://archives.jackbaty.com/images/evernote_logo.gif" title="Evernote" ></p>

<p>I love trying new software. My idea of a fine Sunday afternoon is installing updates and checking out every line in every release note. What this usually means is that I find reasons to try all sorts of applications, even if something I already use would work fine. I rationalize this behavior easily, but the fact is I just like messing around with my &#8220;system&#8221;. Today, while cleaning out my <a href="http://evernote.com">Evernote</a> notebooks, I spotted <a href="http://www.thesecretweapon.org/">The Secret Weapon</a>, &#8220;a no bs approach to personal productivity&#8221;. I read the blog and watched the videos and decided it was a bit too much for me. Besides, I&#8217;m a die-hard OmniFocus nerd. Aren&#8217;t I?</p>

<p>It got me thinking. What if I were to put <em>everything</em> in Evernote? That&#8217;s just crazy talk! After all, I&#8217;m the one who always complains that Evernote makes things too difficult to get back out again. It occurred to me that part of my problem is that it&#8217;s <em>too easy</em> to switch between apps and that the slight friction that Evernote introduces might actually be an advantage.</p>

<p>And so, operation &#8220;Everything Goes Into Evernote&#8221; began today. I&#8217;m using a modified version of The Secret Weapon&#8217;s approach to GTD and put OmniFocus aside for now. I&#8217;ve moved my scanned archives from the powerful DEVONthink Pro into a new Evernote notebook. Project notes have been migrated from VoodooPad. I&#8217;ve even imported my Simplenote notes. I spent a few hours on all of this today, sitting at the iMac on my home office&#8217;s desk. I&#8217;m now sitting in a chair using the MacBook Air and Evernote has synced everything up nicely. Plus, it&#8217;s all on my iPhone. This required no additional sync servers or setup on my part. Encouraging.</p>

<p>And since I tend to go all-in on stuff like this, I installed both Evernote Food and Evernote Hello. <a href="http://ifttt.com">ifttt</a> is bringing in all of my tweets, blog posts, and other favorited/liked content around the web.</p>

<p>This all may become overwhelming to have in one place. I&#8217;m a fan of variety, so there&#8217;s a concern that I&#8217;ll just get bored again quickly. For now, though, everything goes into Evernote.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sad, Beautiful Fact That We're All Going To Miss Almost Everything]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/the-sad/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T09:04:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/the-sad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Linda Holmes for NPR:</p>

<blockquote><p>If &#8220;well-read&#8221; means &#8220;not missing anything,&#8221; then nobody has a chance. If &#8220;well-read&#8221; means &#8220;making a genuine effort to explore thoughtfully,&#8221; then yes, we can all be well-read. But what we&#8217;ve seen is always going to be a very small cup dipped out of a very big ocean, and turning your back on the ocean to stare into the cup can&#8217;t change that.</p></blockquote>

<p>The urge to not miss <em>anything</em> is so strong that I miss <em>important</em> things.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress, Janus, and Zsh]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/octopress-janus-and-zsh/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T15:54:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/octopress-janus-and-zsh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It doesn&#8217;t take much for me to completely reverse direction. Not long ago I loudly proclaimed that the command line and I were going our separate ways. &#8220;I&#8217;m too old to remember all of those damn commands!&#8221; I said. &#8220;Tweaking my Vim and bash settings are nothing but a waste of time!&#8221; I snorted.</p>

<p>Do you know what I did yesterday? I switched my shell to zsh, installed Janus, and moved my blog back to Octopress. It was so much fun I didn&#8217;t know when to quit, so I didn&#8217;t.</p>

<h2>Octopress</h2>

<p><a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> is a very nice wrapper for Jekyll, but anything ruby related tends to cause me grief. It was no different this time. Of course I didn&#8217;t have rvm configured so I started there. Xcode was somehow either too old or otherwise broken and so I would get errors when running bundler. Gave up and updated the ginormous Xcode install and then ran this&#8230;</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>terminal</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>sudo xcode-select -switch /Applications/Xcode.app/Contents/Developer/Platforms/MacOSX.platform/Developer/
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>&#8230;which allowed me to finish installing Octopress. There&#8217;s something wrong with the combination of having system ruby at 1.8.3 or whatever and new Ruby apps wanting some other version. Rvm is supposed to fix this, but for someone like me who only dabbles in Ruby these days, it&#8217;s a pain in the ass.</p>

<p>Converting the posts from my Wordpress blog was made possibly by <a href="https://github.com/thomasf/exitwp">exitwp</a> which converted each post to Markdown and added appropriate YAML front matter to each file. I know, I&#8217;ve <a href="http://jackbaty.com/2011/10/new-blogging-hotness/">gone through this before</a> but this time it coincides with my newfound love for the terminal and text files. Besides, I love having everything I&#8217;ve written on this blog since 2000 safely stored in 1700+ portable markdown files sitting in a folder on my computer. I&#8217;m using the default Octopress theme with a few tweaks to the header and I like it.</p>

<h2>ZSH</h2>

<p>The last thing someone who&#8217;s sworn off the terminal should to is change their shell. I did it anyway. After hearing so many good things about <a href="http://zsh.sourceforge.net/">Z shell</a> I have been tempted to try it, but up until yesterday had backed away slowly. While tinkering, I ran into <a href="https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh">oh-my-zsh</a>, which makes getting a fully configured zsh install easy. I just did this&#8230;</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>terminal</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>curl -L https://github.com/robbyrussell/oh-my-zsh/raw/master/tools/install.sh | sh
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The tab completion in zsh alone is worth the price of a ticket.</p>

<h2>Janus</h2>

<p>The urge to tinker with Vim&#8217;s configuration can chew through most of a developer&#8217;s
life if left unchecked. It&#8217;s fun and addictive, though. I love finding some
obscure setting that suddenly makes one task or another easier. I&#8217;ve got
a few years into my configuration, and just threw most of it out due to
<a href="https://github.com/carlhuda/janus">Janus</a>. Janus is a distribution of
plugins, key mappings etc. for Vim and MacVim. It pulls in the best of
thousands of plugins and configures them in a consistent, simple way.
Anything can be overridden, so it works as a nice clean head start.
Installation is a matter of running one command&#8230;</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>terminal</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>curl -Lo- http://bit.ly/janus-bootstrap | bash
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I still symlink my dotfiles into a dropbox directory so changes on one
machine are automatically included on the others. I could use Git for this,
and probably should, but so far the Dropbox sync works pretty well. Plus,
I don&#8217;t have to remember to push anything.</p>

<p>All of this has been a great deal of fun, and of course I keep learning
things each time I go through the process. Onward!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OfflineIMAP is archiving all of my email]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/offlineimap-is-current-archiving-all-of-my-email/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-26T17:42:13-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/offlineimap-is-current-archiving-all-of-my-email</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The email geekery continues this weekend.</p>

<p>After using Mutt with Gmail&#8217;s IMAP for the past week or so, I&#8217;m finally getting comfortable again. It&#8217;s been a long time, but Mutt is just really fast and fun to use, once everything is configured nicely. The slow link in the chain now is the network lag when accessing IMAP mailboxes remotely. To work around that, I configured <a href="http://offlineimap.org/">OfflineIMAP</a> and it&#8217;s now syncing all of my Gmail locally.</p>

<p><img src="http://archives.jackbaty.com/images/2012/02/offline.jpg" alt="Offline" /></p>

<p>This is great because it kills another bird: Archiving. I don&#8217;t know about you, but I get a little twitchy thinking about all of my emails sitting out there on Gmails servers, just waiting for some excuse to prevent me from getting to them. With OfflineIMAP running, every single one of those emails becomes a text file on my local machine. I find that comforting.</p>

<p>Once it&#8217;s done syncing I&#8217;ll be able to access everything locally using Mutt, and have every change made reflected back up to Gmail. There are a few stray gotchas still in my way, like dealing with Gmail&#8217;s annoying Priority Inbox handling, and the All Mail duplicate problem, but I have some ideas there that I will try once things are running smoothly.</p>

<p>A few links to pages that helped me through this process&#8230;</p>

<p><a href="http://offlineimap.org/">http://offlineimap.org/</a><br/>
<a href="http://pbrisbin.com/posts/mutt_gmail_offlineimap">http://pbrisbin.com/posts/mutt_gmail_offlineimap</a><br/>
<a href="http://www.h4ck3r.net/2011/03/13/gmail-backup-imap/">http://www.h4ck3r.net/2011/03/13/gmail-backup-imap/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I just can't seem to shake VIM]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/i-just-cant-seem-to-shake-vim/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-26T14:05:18-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/i-just-cant-seem-to-shake-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remember a few months ago when I said that I had permanently deleted MacVim from my machine(s) and was going BBEdit/GUI forever? Yeah, about that.</p>

<p>My recently renewed <a href="http://jackbaty.com/2012/02/mutt-makes-for-powerful-email/">fascination with Mutt</a> reminded me how truly nice it can be editing text with <a href="http://www.vim.org/">VIM</a>. So I&#8217;ve installed <a href="http://code.google.com/p/macvim/">MacVim</a> once again and spent some time tweaking my <a href="https://gist.github.com/1918237">.vimrc</a> file. I know, the urge to tweak the .vimrc file is one of the reasons I decided to stop using VIM in the first place. I contain multitudes, no?</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve tried keeping things to a miniumum this time, but there are some plugins I can&#8217;t live without. Here are the ones I&#8217;m running this time:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/mileszs/ack.vim">Ack</a> - Uses Ack for searches</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/scrooloose/nerdtree">nerdtree</a> - The only file browser I&#8217;ve ever been able to deal with</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/altercation/vim-colors-solarized">vim-colors-solarized</a> - Nice color scheme based on Ethan Schoonover&#8217;s palettes.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-fugitive">vim-fugitive</a> - &#8220;a Git wrapper so awesome, it should be illegal&#8221;</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-markdown">vim-markdown</a> - Helpers for writing in Markdown</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/vim-pandoc/vim-pandoc">vim-pandoc</a> - Helpers for converting files using Pandoc</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/topfunky/PeepOpen-EditorSupport/tree/master/vim-peepopen">vim-peepopen</a> - Interface to the PeepOpen app</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-repeat">vim-repeat</a>  Better handling of the repeat &#8220;.&#8221; command</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/honza/writer.vim">writer.vim</a> - Simple plugin that makes writing prose in VIM nicer</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mutt Makes for Powerful Email]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/mutt-makes-for-powerful-email/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-20T22:20:40-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/mutt-makes-for-powerful-email</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven&#8217;t used <a href="http://mutt.org/">Mutt</a> for email since sometime around 2004. At some point I tired of dealing with attachments and links and too many HTML-only emails and started using a normal GUI email client like everyone else.</p>

<p>This past weekend I was becoming terribly annoyed by how slow Mail.app had become. Every click meant a lag before what was supposed to happen happened. For the hell of it, I thought I&#8217;d play with Mutt again, even though I knew that it would probably be a complete pain. I was wrong.</p>

<p>Things have gotten easier in the nearly 10 years since I last installed it. A simple &#8220;brew install mutt&#8221; and a few gmail IMAP and SMTP settings and I was in. No MTAs or Fetchmail or Procmail or OfflineIMAP. Everything just worked with one quick install.</p>

<p>And then the tweaking inevitably began. I&#8217;ve got my keybinding configured to match Gmail. Added lbdb to search Address Book for email lookups. Added some VIM-specific config so that wrapping and highlighting do the right thing. You know, tweaking.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t know how long I&#8217;ll stick with it, but Mutt is damn fast and damn powerful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[batyphoto.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/batyphoto-com/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-11T12:07:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/batyphoto-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I&#8217;ve finally gotten into the Squarespace 6 beta I thought I&#8217;d use it to create a proper photo blog. Or try to. It&#8217;s still new and may or may not stick around, but why not?</p>

<p><a href="http://batyphoto.com/">batyphoto.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recipe Box]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/recipe-box/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-11T10:14:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/recipe-box</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://archives.jackbaty.com/images/2012/02/20120129_DSCF0338.jpg" alt="20120129 DSCF0338" /></p>

<p>I don&#8217;t cook very often. You can tell by the contents of my recipe box. Most of the recipes were given to me by my mother many years ago and have only been used once or twice since. Even so, this ugly wooden box is precious to me. Those cards were handwritten by someone I love and who loves me. They&#8217;re permanent and meaningful, and I&#8217;ll always know where they are.</p>

<p>I realize that it would be more convenient to use an iPad to store recipes, but I&#8217;m not going to do that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Olympus OM-D]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/olympus-om-d/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T22:06:33-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/02/olympus-om-d</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://archives.jackbaty.com/images/2012/02/Olympus-OM-1n.jpg" alt="Olympus OM 1n" /></p>

<p>One of my favorite cameras ever is a beat up Olympus OM-1n I picked up on Craigslist for next to nothing. It&#8217;s compact, nicely built, and the OM lenses are terrific. I love that camera.</p>

<p>When Olympus started the recent retro fad with the E-P1 I fell in love and bought one. The E-P1 was a nice camera (is a nice camera, I still have it) but lacked a viewfinder. I need a viewfinder. Also, the focus was quite slow. When the E-P3 finally came out things had improved quite a bit, so I bought one along with the very nice electronic viewfinder. I prefer optical viewfinders, but the EVF on the E-P3 is very good. What&#8217;s not so great is that it uses the hot shoe, and looks silly.</p>

<p>Enter the OM-D E-M5.</p>

<p><img src="http://archives.jackbaty.com/images/2012/02/om-d.png" alt="Olympus OM-D" /></p>

<p>This one ticks almost all of the boxes. If the AF is as fast as they claim, I may just pick one up. I have a couple of really nice m4/3rd lenses already, plus the M-mount adapter for the Leica lenses.</p>

<p>I suppose this means the E-P1 and E-P3 are for sale.</p>

<p>See:<br/>
<a href="http://olympusamerica.com/cpg_section/product.asp?product=1583">Olympus Product Page</a><br/>
<a href="http://visualsciencelab.blogspot.com/2012/02/olympus-fans-rejoice-om-d-is-real-and.html">Kirk Tuck&#8217;s early notes</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happiness Takes (A Little) Magic | The Wirecutter]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/happiness-takes-a-little-magic-the-wirecutter/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-29T08:33:46-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/happiness-takes-a-little-magic-the-wirecutter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8220;Technology lets us do things faster and more efficiently; why would we use that newfound free time to do more and more of the same old thing?  I&#8217;m not just talking about smarter consumption of content like Johnson is– I&#8217;m also saying, fuck consumption.&#8221;</p></blockquote>

<p>I&#8217;ve been thinking along these lines a lot lately. Something&#8217;s gotta happen.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Trusty Stylus Epic]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/my-trusty-stylus-epic/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-28T18:16:54-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/my-trusty-stylus-epic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2004, during one of my many film-digital-film waffle sessions, I picked up an old <a href="http://jackbaty.com/2004/07/olympus-stylus-epic/">Stylus Epic</a> for use as my &#8220;every day carry&#8221; camera.</p>

<p><img src="http://dl.dropbox.com/u/11319/copingmechanism/stylus-epic.jpg" alt="Stylus Epic" /></p>

<p>Many of the cameras I buy for specific reasons turn out to have been wishful thinking. Not so the Epic. I still carry it in my jacket pocket every day. Most of the lettering is worn off, but it still works great. And it&#8217;s still the easiest and fastest pocket camera I&#8217;ve every used. It has a very nice lens and would be quite cheap to replace. I see no reason I won&#8217;t be carrying one of these indefinitely.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
