<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | Jack Baty - the archives]]></title>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T23:15:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack Baty]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jack@jackbaty.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Everything Must Go]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/09/movie-everything-must-go/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-05T17:12:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/09/movie-everything-must-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2011/09/everything-must-go.jpg" alt="Everything must go" /></p>

<p>Will Ferrell is terrific in <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1531663/">Everything Must Go</a>. It's nice to see him take on a more dramatic, nearly dead-pan role as Nick Halsey, a recovering alcoholic who quickly becomes jobless, wifeless, and homeless.</p>

<p>My sporadic minimalist tendencies helped me enjoy watching Nick first struggle with, then shed everything he owned. I suddenly feel like grabbing a six-pack of PBR and having a yard sale.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Thor]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/09/thor/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-05T10:58:19-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/09/thor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2011/09/thor-movie.jpg" alt="Thor movie" /></p>

<p>I don't enjoy comic books, but movies based on comic books can be fun. Thor was not one of those movies. Way too much time was spent showing me how awesome CGI scenes can be. Asgard was crazily overwrought. I'll need to watch Metropolis again to cleanse my palate. The bad guy was a pussy with a remote controlled giant robot. I was embarrassed by how Natalie Portman ogled and stammered every time Thor was within pheromone range.</p>

<p>The biggest surprise was Chris Hemsworth, who I found to do a decent job of playing the meat-headed doofus with a hammer. I spent much of the movie amazed by how much Keira Knightley looks like Natalie Portman. Imagine my embarrassment when the credits rolled.</p>

<p>Overall, Thor does what I'd guess it set out to do, but I wish it hadn't.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ebert reviews Battle: Los Angeles]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/03/ebert-reviews-battle-los-angeles/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-12T12:16:50-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/03/ebert-reviews-battle-los-angeles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID=/20110309/REVIEWS/110309992">Battle: Los Angeles :: rogerebert.com</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>"'Battle: Los Angeles' is noisy, violent, ugly and stupid. Its manufacture is a reflection of appalling cynicism on the part of its makers, who don't even try to make it more than senseless chaos. Here's a science-fiction film that's an insult to the words 'science' and 'fiction,' and the hyphen in between them. You want to cut it up to clean under your fingernails."</p></blockquote>

<p>I sometimes wish studios would make even <em>more</em> movies like Battle: Los Angeles, just so Ebert can write about them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
