<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Film | Jack Baty - the archives]]></title>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/blog/categories/film/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T23:15:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack Baty]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jack@jackbaty.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deciding between the old and the new]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/04/deciding-between-the-old-and-the-new/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T15:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/04/deciding-between-the-old-and-the-new</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2012/fuji-and-m4.jpg" alt="Fuji X-Pro1 and Leica M4" /></p>

<p>I'm never going to "go completely digital" or "use only film" since I cannot completely give up either. Not that I haven't tried. One day I convince myself the only thing that matters is film, and I buy the greatest film camera I can think of because that's all I'll ever need or use ever ever again. A week (or month) goes by and I decide I'm frustrated with scanning or whatever and I think I'd prefer something quick and easy, so I find some new hot digital camera that will solve all my problems.</p>

<p>It's never going to end, I know that. But knowing doesn't help.</p>

<p>For example, I recently had a disappointing week shooting film in low light. Tri-X shot at 1250 ISO and processed in Diafine does pretty well, but even that pushes shutter speeds down to 1/30th or so and inevitably motion blur ruins everything. Tired of fighting it, I looked to digital.</p>

<p>I "solved" the problem by buying a Fuji X-Pro1 and a couple of lenses. How does that solve the problem? Well, I love the hybrid viewfinder, analog controls, and of course the excellent high ISO performance. ISO 6400 is usable, and The Fujinon 35mm 1.4 is plenty fast. Boom! It's like best of both worlds.</p>

<p>Except then I picked up my trusty Leica M4. There's nothing like the feel of that camera. It's visceral. Besides, what else does one need? No batteries or whizbang features to get in the way. Pure photography! And I have an awesome and under-utilized wet darkroom just begging for more film, so I start shopping again.</p>

<p>You see how it is? It's a grand form of rationalization. Eventually, I'll need to accept the fact that I really love the very old film process as well as and the very newest digital wizardry. It'll have to be both. There, that's settled. Right?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favorite Movies of 2009]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/12/favorite-movies-of-2009/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-27T09:58:23-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/12/favorite-movies-of-2009</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here's a quick list of my favorite movies from the past year.</p>

<h3>The Hangover</h3>

<p><img src="/images/thehangovermovie.jpg" alt="thehangovermovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>Saw the poster for The Hangover while seeing another movie. Made a mental note to avoid it. I was wrong. Funny from start to finish.</p>

<h3>The Class</h3>

<p><img src="/images/theclassmovie.jpg" alt="theclassmovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>Should have been cliche, but wasn't. It was quiet, real and moving.</p>

<h3>The Hurt Locker</h3>

<p><img src="/images/hurtlockermovie.jpg" alt="hurtlockermovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>Devastating, tense, thrilling. A character study rather than a "war movie."</p>

<h3>Up!</h3>

<p><img src="/images/upmovie.jpg" alt="upmovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>The first 15 minutes of <em>Up!</em> prove once again that animation can be deeply emotional and SQUIRREL!</p>

<h3>Zombieland</h3>

<p><img src="/images/zombielandmovie.jpg" alt="zombielandmovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>Who know the zombie genre had so much life left in it. Also includes the best cameo ever.</p>

<h3>Inglourious Basterds</h3>

<p><img src="/images/inglouriousbasterdsmovie.jpg" alt="inglouriousbasterdsmovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>Brad Pitt's over the top character was fine, but Nazi Colonel Hans Landa (Christoph Waltz) walked away with every scene he was in. I don't automatically love everything Tarantino does, but I loved Inglourious Basterds.</p>

<h3>Goodbye Solo</h3>

<p><img src="/images/goodbyesolomovie.jpg" alt="goodbyesolomovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>Quiet, understated, touching. I was completely engrossed from start to finish.</p>

<h3>Anvil! The Story of Anvil</h3>

<p><img src="/images/storyofanvilmovie.jpg" alt="storyofanvilmovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>You don't have to be a Metal fan to enjoy watching Anvil! The Story of Anvil. It's touching, sad and hopeful and funny.</p>

<h3>In The Loop</h3>

<p><img src="/images/intheloopmovie.jpg" alt="intheloopmovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>Fast, hilarious, vicious political satire. This is how wars are made.</p>

<h3>World's Greatest Dad</h3>

<p><img src="/images/worldsgreatestdadmovie.jpg" alt="worldsgreatestdadmovie.jpg" /></p>

<p>This dark, perverted, and very funny movie by Bob Goldthwait took me completely by surprise. I've grown to expect less from Robin Williams, but he's terrific here. I guess a little autoerotic asphyxiation brings out the best in people.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Self-Manufacture of Megan Fox - NYTimes.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/11/the-self-manufacture-of-megan-fox-nytimes-com/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-12T14:32:16-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/11/the-self-manufacture-of-megan-fox-nytimes-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>NYTimes on Megan Fox:</p>

<blockquote><p>Fox has a quality that sets her apart: Fox is sly. Canny. A devoted student of stardom, past and present, she knows how to provide her own color commentary -- a narrative to go with the underwear.</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="/images/meganfox.jpg" alt="meganfox.jpg" /></p>

<p>Inez van Lamsweerde and Vinoodh Matadin for The New York Times</p>

<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/11/15/magazine/15Fox-t.html?_r=2&amp;ref=magazine&amp;pagewanted=all">NYTimes</a></p>

<p>I have such a crush on Ms. Fox. I know it's wrong, but I just can't help it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Max Payne (ful)]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/01/max-payne-ful/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-24T00:18:58-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/01/max-payne-ful</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/max-payne.jpg" alt="max-payne.jpg" /></p>

<p>I can't remember the last time I saw a movie this bad. Poor Wahlberg just can't catch a break. He sure can scowl though. Painful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ebert asks himself the question.]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2008/09/ebert-asks-himself-the-question/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-04T20:28:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2008/09/ebert-asks-himself-the-question</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you've not been reading "Roger Ebert's blog":http://blogs.suntimes.com/ebert/, you should. He writes well, writes passionately, and best of all, writes about things I'm interested in.</p>

<p>In his latest post, "What's your favorite movie":http://blogs.suntimes.com/ebert/2008/09/whats_your_favorite_movie.html, he asks himself that very question. His answer? La Dolce Vita. Great, great choice, but his reason for choosing it is less about the film than it is about himself. That seems fair.</p>

<p><img src="/images//la-dolce-vita.jpg" alt="la-dolce-vita.jpg" /></p>

<p>Mine? If I had to answer right now, I'd say Dr. Strangelove. Too bad Anita Ekberg isn't in it though.</p>

<p><img src="/images//dr-strangelove.jpg" alt="dr_strangelove.jpg" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
