<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: News | Jack Baty - the archives]]></title>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T23:15:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack Baty]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jack@jackbaty.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Together Forever]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/11/together-forever/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-15T13:57:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/11/together-forever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Washington City Paper on Recycling and Trash: Together Forever:</p>

<blockquote><p>After the truck releases the Dumpster, the garbagemen get their hands on something that doesn't mix well with all that rotting garbage: the recycling. They roll up with bins holding newspaper, cardboard, bottles, and cans -- all dutifully separated by employees at the bookstore and other businesses on this upper Connecticut Avenue strip. One by one, the men tip the contents of the recycling containers on top of the refuse -- the bottles make a tinkling sound as the glass shatters against the truck bed.</p>

<p>Then: They go back to collecting trash. The driver hits a switch and it's all smashed together before disappearing into the belly of the truck."</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://www.washingtoncitypaper.com/printerpage.php?id=38060">Washington City Paper</a></p>

<p>I know I'm supposed to recycle, but I usually don't. Neither do you, eventually.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Everybody Hurts]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/02/everybody-hurts/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-02T18:42:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2009/02/everybody-hurts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://davenetics.com/2009/02/everybody-hurts/">Everybody Hurts</a></p>

<blockquote><p>It seems to me, as the end of the first half approaches, that the theme of this year's Super Bowl XLIII Ads is extreme violence done to one's person.</p></blockquote>

<p>(Via <a href="http://davenetics.com">Davenetics</a>.)</p>

<p>That is exactly what I thought after the first half. That, and a little misogyny thrown in for good measure. Glad I'm not the only one who wondered if all the agencies had some sort of meeting pre-game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jon Stewart on the gender card]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2008/09/jon-stewart-on-the-gender-card/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-06T08:26:08-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2008/09/jon-stewart-on-the-gender-card</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love Jon Stewart. This video is everywhere, but on the slim chance you haven't seen it...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Save Rachel Ray]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2008/05/save-rachel-ray/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-29T18:36:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2008/05/save-rachel-ray</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/rachael_ray.jpg" alt="rachael_ray.ap.03.jpg" /></p>

<p>So Rachel Ray wears a scarf in a Dunkin Donuts ad. Conservative columnist Michelle Malkin decides that since a number of bad guys have worn similar scarves that the ad is somehow sympathetic with terrorists. <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2008/05/29/news/companies/dunkin_donuts.ap/">The ad is pulled</a>. Seems that wearing a certain type of scarf (a "kaffiyeh") "…has come to symbolize murderous Palestinian jihad."</p>

<p>That strikes me as nonsense. According to wikipedia…</p>

<blockquote><p>Since the beginning of the War on Terror, these keffiyeh, usually cotton and in military olive drab or khaki with black stitching, have been adopted by US and troops as well. Their practicality in an arid environment, as in Iraq, explains their constant popularity with soldiers. Soldiers often wear the keffiyeh folded in half into a triangle and wrapped around the face, with the halfway point being placed over the mouth and nose, sometimes coupled with goggles, to keep sand out of the face.</p></blockquote>

<p>But also…</p>

<blockquote><p>The keffiyeh has become a symbol of the Palestinians in the long running Israeli-Palestinian conflict. As a result of its symbolic meaning in this context, its display in the West has periodically been the subject of criticism.</p></blockquote>

<p>To a delusional paranoid conservative columnist, I guess it could be mis-construed - somehow. To the rest of us, it's just a friggin' scarf.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Strange Maps: An Absolut Mexico]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2008/04/strange-maps-an-absolut-mexico/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-06T08:30:26-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2008/04/strange-maps-an-absolut-mexico</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Absolut Vodka ad released in Mexico has me feeling all defensive, for honestly no good reason.</p>

<p><img src="/images/absolutmexico.jpg" alt="absolutmexico.jpg" /></p>

<p>(Via <a href="http://strangemaps.wordpress.com">strange maps</a>.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
