<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Photography | Jack Baty - the archives]]></title>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/blog/categories/photography/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T23:15:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jack Baty]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jack@jackbaty.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 Photo Album]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/2012-photo-album/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T18:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/03/2012-photo-album</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% img /images/20120319__DSC5849-processed.jpg %}</p>

<p>I'm building an honest-to-goodness photo album this year. Each print is made in
the darkroom and each caption is hand-written. Not a pixel in sight.</p>

<p>It's a hand-made family heirloom, that's what it is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laugh]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/laugh/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-22T16:55:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/laugh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/2012/01/Laugh.jpg"><img src="/images/2012/01/Laugh.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I love this photo. It's from a set of early 1900s negatives I picked up at a garage sale. The expression on the man's face makes me smile every time I look at it. I like it so much in fact that I've made it my new avatar.</p>

<p>Looking through old photos is something I never tire of. What I find sad is that everyone in this set of photos is almost certainly dead now. I've not been able to determine who these people are, but I would love to find their children or grandchildren and return the negatives to them. Not everyone cares as much about this sort of thing as I do, but c'mon, who wouldn't love to suddenly find a couple hundred lost photos of their great grandparents?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A few more found negatives]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/a-few-more-found-negatives/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-21T15:19:45-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/a-few-more-found-negatives</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Someone asked me about a photo that I'd scanned a couple years ago, so I went into my Lightroom library to dig it up. I couldn't find it. Many of the other scans from that same batch of found negatives were there, but a number of them seemed to have gone missing. I thought making things digital was supposed to make it <em>easier</em> to store and find things. Apparently, I've not figured out how to do that yet, so I pulled the original negatives and found the ones I wanted in about 30 seconds.</p>

<p>While they were out I scanned a few more that I missed or otherwise skipped last time. I find them fascinating.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2012/01/old-neg001.jpg" alt="People playing cards" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2012/01/old-neg002.jpg" alt="I wonder what these folks are doing" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2012/01/old-neg003.jpg" alt="Girl holding kittens" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2012/01/old-neg004.jpg" alt="Baby chewing stick" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2012/01/old-neg005.jpg" alt="Man on Indian motorcycle" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2012/01/old-neg006.jpg" alt="Women in boat on Reeds Lake" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tweetage Wasteland : We All Have Photographic Memories]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/tweetage-wasteland-we-all-have-photographic-memories/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-08T12:04:46-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2012/01/tweetage-wasteland-we-all-have-photographic-memories</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dave Pell:</p>

<blockquote><p>The wave of emotions, senses and reactions that made up his initial experience were swept away by the undertow of a single sense: what his eyes saw on a two inch viewfinder.</p></blockquote>

<p>That describes another negative side effect of the immediate "convenience" of digital photography. We experience less.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Too Perfect]]></title>
    <link href="http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/12/too-perfect/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-30T16:38:01-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archives.jackbaty.com/2011/12/too-perfect</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Nikon D700 creates images as perfect as can be, which is why I'm selling mine.</p>

<p>I love the way the D700 focuses lightning fast, all the time, in any conditions. I love how the images are noise-free way up to ISO 6400 and beyond. I love that I can strap a flash on it and get perfectly lit shots every time. It's all so perfect. If an image isn't perfect, I can twiddle a few dials in Capture One and make it perfect.</p>

<p>It's kind of boring.</p>

<p>I get caught up in the quest for image quality all the time. By that I mean <em>technical</em> quality. The internet makes this easy. Just visit any online forum and you'll find an endless stream of people comparing 100% crops. "By god that lens is so sharp all the way to the corners!" "I prefer the higher contrast and bokeh of the 3rd version." Then I'm all I GOTTA HAVE IT! It gets to the point that any photo that <em>isn't</em> technically perfect is crap.</p>

<p>Chuck Norris, who must use a D700 or something close to it, (probably) once said, "If your camera takes a photo of a coffee mug and my camera takes a photo of a coffee mug, my photo is better than yours." Of course he misses the point that it's still just a photo of a coffee mug. Unless you're doing brochure shots for a local coffee house, who cares?</p>

<p>For non-professionals, the quest for technical perfection in photography is a distraction.</p>

<p>Avoiding the technical quality rat-race is one reason I enjoy shooting film. Film cameras are never going to be any better than they were 10 years ago. Film and film processing are not going to change much either. What we're left with is working with what we've got. I sometimes forget how helpful that can be, creatively. Constraints and all that. I sometimes appear to be trying to getting around that loophole by buying all kinds of different cameras. However, I don't do that in a search for better image quality, but rather for handling or specific interesting features.</p>

<p>Shooting a 36-exposure roll of film usually yields 3 or 4 decent shots for me. Even the best of them still show some signs of grain. in other words, none of them are perfect. I love those shots, imperfect as they may be. Shooting with the D700 I'll bring home a card with 400 or 500 shots on it, 300 of which are technically pretty close to perfect. Who wants to sort through all those and keep track of them forever? I'm ultimately happier with my 3 or 4 crappy film shots.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
